A Guide to the Virginia Place Name Society Records, 1947-1982
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Place Name Society Records, 1947-1982
The Library of Virginia
31412
22.6 cubic feet (57 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Virginia Place Name Society, Charlottesville.
Historical Information
The Virginia Place Name Society was organized on 28 June 1960 in order to promote place name research in Virginia and to encourage by appropriate means systematic surveying and publication of place name information and findings. In addition, the Society acted as a clearinghouse for such information and made available place name publications. The administration of the Society was conducted by a board of directors which included a president, vice-president, secretary, treasurer and publications director. The Society's publications included Occasional Papers, which presented findings from a variety of place name related research projects. The Society also published six newsletters during 1972-1979. Due to a lack of funds and a declining interest by persons dedicated to carrying on the work of the Society, the organization dissolved in 1982.
The Place Name Survey of the United States' purpose was to survey, state by state, place name information on United States place names with a view toward making the assembled information available to interested persons. The organization established guidelines for all field work methods to ensure the research was valid. The Place Name Survey of Virginia was a subsidiary and regional branch of the Place Name Survey of the United States. Members of the Virginia Place Name Society were closely affiliated with the Place Name Survey of Virginia. Powell Burwell Rogers was the director of the Place Name Survey of the United States until his death. He was succeeded by Douglas W. Tanner.
Scope and Content
Records, 1947-1982, of the Virginia Place Name Society, including of the papers of Raus M. Hanson (1889-1982) and Powell Burwell Rogers (1909-1976), administrative files of the Virginia Place Name Society, and the files of the Place Name Survey of Virginia. The collection contains clippings, correspondence, financial records, membership records, minutes, newsletters, Occasional Papers, publications, and other materials.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following record groups, based on the original order and numbering system:
I. Raus M. Hanson Papers (Part I and II).
II. Powell Burwell Rogers Papers.
III. Virginia Place Name Society Files.
IV. Place Name Survey of Virginia Files.
Contents List
- Series I. Raus M. Hanson Papers, 1965-1974., Extent: 16 boxes. (Box 1-16)
  The Raus M. Hanson Papers are divided into two parts. Part I includes research files for place name studies that were conducted after the publication of his book entitled VIRGINIA PLACE NAMES: DERIVATIONS, HISTORICAL USES (1969), including clippings, correspondence, notes, pamphlets and publications. The files are arranged alphabetically by place name and other files are arranged alphabetically by county. Part II contains both typed and handwritten manuscripts of entries and chapters of his book, as well as correspondence with researchers concerning various Virginia place names. This correspondence is arranged by the county containing the place of interest.
  - Part I - Correspondence, 1974-1975. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Part I - Index (By County). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Part I - Aaron's Creek - Basham. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Part I - Bassett Forks - Blunt Point. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Part I - Bobbitt Knob - Byrdton. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Part I - Cabin Creek - Chestnut Ridge. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Part I - Childress - Cypress Swamp. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Part I - Dale Enterprise - Dymer Creek. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Part I - Eagle Eeyree - Floyd's Bay. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Part I - Folly Mills Creek - Gypsy Hill. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Part I - Hagan - Hyco River. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Part I - Iberia - Kratzer Road. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Part I - Lacey Springs - Locust Hill. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Part I - Lodge - Menokin. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Part I - Merchant's Hope Church - Myers House. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Part I - Naked Creek - Oyster Point. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Part I - Paddy's Knob - Powhite Creek. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Part I - Prater - Russell Prater Creek. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Part I - Sabine Hall - Snow Creek. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Part I - Soapstone Branch - Syms Eaton Academy. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Part I - Tabscott - Wakefield. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Part I - Wakenva - Zion Crossroads. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Part I - Notes for Preface to "Enlarged Addition". (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Part I - Miscellaneous. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Part I - Accomack - Cumberland. (Box 5, Folder 1-25)
  - Part I - Dickenson - James City. (Box 6, Folder 1-22)
  - Part I - King and Queen - New Kent. (Box 7, Folder 1-16)
  - Part I - Northampton - Smyth. (Box 8, Folder 1-21)
  - Part I - Southampton - York. (Box 9, Folder 1-12)
  - Part I - County Files: Towns Without Derivations. (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Part I - Independent Cities: Needing Derivations. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Part II - Typed Manuscript, Counties. (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
  - Part II - Typed Manuscript, Independent Cities. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Counties. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Independent Cities. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Part II - Manuscript Draft, Index. (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Part II - Typed Manuscript, Larger Areas. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Larger Areas: Aaron's Creek - Butt Mountain. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Larger Areas: Calfpasture River - Fredericksburg Park. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Larger Areas: Gallion State Forest - Muddy Creek. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Larger Areas: Naked Creek - Rye Valley. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Larger Areas: St. Luke's Church - York River. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Abingdon - Azalea. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Back Bay - Bybee. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Collands - Customhouse. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Dabneys - Fulks Run. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Gainesboro - Hylas. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Independence - Lynnhaven. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: McClure - Nuttsville. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Oak Grove - Ruthville. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Saint Brides - Syringa. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Towns, etc: Tabb - Zuni. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, County-by-County: Amherst - Highland. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, County-by-County: Isle of Wight - York. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Part II - Typed Draft: Railroads. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Part II - Manuscript Draft, Listing of Place Names: Advance Mills - Zanda. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Part II - Manuscript Draft, Listing of Water Features: Appomattox Reservoir - Wilson Creek. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Part II - Typed Draft, Listing of Mountains (in order of height). (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Accomack - Amelia). (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Amherst - Augusta). (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Bath - Botetourt). (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Brunswick - Campbell). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Caroline - Charlotte). (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Chesterfield - Culpeper). (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Cumberland - Essex). (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Fairfax - Fluvanna). (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Franklin - Gloucester). (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Goochland - Greensville). (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Halifax - Henry). (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Highland - King and Queen). (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Part II - Correspondence (King George - Lee). (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Loudoun - Madison). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Mathews - Montgomery). (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Nansemond - Page). (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Patrick - Russell). (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Scott - York). (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Part II - Correspondence (Alexandria - Virginia Beach). (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Part II - Correspondence - General. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Part II - Correspondence - Railroads. (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
  - Part II - Publication of "Virginia Place Names". (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Part II - Notes re: "Virginia Place Names". (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Part II - Clippings. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Series II. Powell Burwell Rogers Papers, 1952-1976., Extent: 13 boxes. (Box 17-29)
  The Powell Burwell Rogers Papers include clippings, correspondence, publications, and place name research and card files.
  - Publications. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - First Names in Virginia. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Counties. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - American and Virginia Place Name Societies. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Names - General. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Place Name Survey of the United States. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Virginia - Consolidation of Cities and Counties - Clippings. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Virginia - Names, Places. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Virginia - Names, Places. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Gloucester County - Names. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Hampton - Names. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Isle of Wight, Surry - Names. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Newport News - Names. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Williamsburg, James City County - Names. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - York County - Names. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Astronauts - Names. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Church Names. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Covered Bridges. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Ships' Names. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Card Files (Miscellaneous). (Box 19)
  - Card Files (Accomack - Campbell). (Box 20)
  - Card Files (Caroline - Franklin). (Box 21)
  - Card Files (Frederick - King William). (Box 22)
  - Card Files (Lancaster - Northumberland). (Box 23)
  - Card Files (Nottoway - Shenandoah). (Box 24)
  - Card Files (Smyth - Wythe, General, and Plantations). (Box 25)
  - Card Files (Hampton, Newport News, Richmond, Williamsburg, and Sources). (Box 26)
  - Card Files (Charles City, Henrico, James City, New Kent, and York). (Box 27)
  - Card Files (Miscellaneous, Terms, and Sources). (Box 28-29)
- Series III. Virginia Place Name Society Files, 1947-1982., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 30-39)
  The Virginia Place Name Society Files include general files, correspondence files, workshops and conferences, membership records, Occasional Papers, newsletters, and financial records.
  - General Files - Ad Hoc Committee on Reorganization. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - General Files - American Name Society, 1967-1974. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - General Files - Approved Place Names in Virgina (Manuscript). (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - General Files - Approved Place Names in Virginia (Partial Draft). (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - General Files - Approved Place Names in Virginia (Reviews, Correspondence, etc.). (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (A-E), 1960-1971. (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (F-J), 1960-1971. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (K-N), 1960-1971. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (K-N), 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (O-R), 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (S), 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - General Files - Correspondence, Dues, Orders, etc. (T-Z), 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - General Files - Place Names (A-L) 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - General Files - Place Names (M-Z) 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - General Files - Queries, Clippings, Sources. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Files - Director/President, 1973-1978. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Files - Dunbar, Gary S.. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Files - Ehrensperger, E.C.. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Files - General, 1947-1972. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Files - General, 1973-1975. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Files - General, 1976-1977. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Files - General, 1978-1981. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Files - Gilliam, Charles Edgar. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Files - Publications - Orders Paid, 1977-1979. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Files - Publications - Orders Unpaid, 1977-1978. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Files - Publications - Inquiries, 1977. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Files - Publications - Pat Due Accounts and Orders, 1972, 1980. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Files - Publications and Orders, 1972-1975. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Workshops and Conferences, 1972-1979. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Membership Records - Life Memberships. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Membership Records - Membership Applications. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Membership Records - Notice Concerning Dues, 1968. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Membership Records, 1972. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Membership Records, 1973. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Membership Records, 1974. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Membership Records, 1975. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Membership Records, 1976-1977. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Membership Records, 1978. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Membership Records, 1979. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Membership Records, 1980. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Membership Records - Index Cards. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 1 (Dunbar, Gary S. "A Preliminary Bibliography of Virginia Place-Name Literature"), 1961. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 2 ("Being an Index to John Speed's Map of Virginia and Maryland, 1676"), 1961. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 3 (Manahan, John E. "Analysis of Virginia Place-Names as to Origin"), 1961. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 4 (Dunbar, Gary S. "Some Notes on Bison in Early Virginia"), 1962. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 5 (Deal, N. Harvey "Ah Sid, Yellow Jacket Town, Blacks and Whites"), 1962. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 6 (Index to the Surface Waters of Virginia"), 1962. (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 7 (Wyllie, John Cook "Meadow Branch, the Stream East of Monticello, Lately Called Tufton Branch, with Some Notes on the Nearby Surface Waters"), 1962. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 8 (Williams, David Alan "Manassas Gap"), 1963. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 9 (Wyllie, John Cook "Totier Creek: A First Families of Albemarle Place Name"), 1963. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 10 (Deal, N. Harvey "The Mountains of Virginia"), 1964. (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 11 (Manahan, John E. "British Origins of Names of Some Old Virginia Homes" and Hench, Atcheson L. "Richmond's Kissing Lane"), 1966. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 12 (Rogers, P. Burwell "The First Names of Virginia"), 1967. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 13 (Murphy, Mary Catherine "Index to Green Peyton's A Map of Albemarle County"), 1967. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 14 (Virginia Place Name Society "Prospectus"), 1961. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 15 (Topping, Mary "Approved Place Names in Virginia: An Index to Virginia Names Approved by the United States Board on Geographic Names Through 1969"), 1969. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 16 (Rogers, P. Burwell "Virginia Counties"), 1972. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 17 (Bristol, Roger P. "Greene County Place Names"), 1974. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 18 (Bristol, Roger P. "Approved Place Names in Virginia: An Index to Virginia Names Approved by the United States Board on Geographic Names From 1970 Through 1973"), 1974. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 19 (Gordon, James W., Jr. "French Place Names in Virginia"), 1975. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 20 (Tanner, Douglas W. "A Handbook for Place Name Research in Virginia"), 1976. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Occasional Papers - No. 21 (Tanner, Douglas W. "Madison County Place Names"), 1978. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, Nos. 1-6, 1972-1979. (Box 37, Folder 6-10)
  - Financial Records, 1961-1964. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, 1965-1966. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records, 1967-1971. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records, 1971-1972. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Financial Records, 1973-1974. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records, 1975-1977. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records, 1978. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Financial Records, 1979. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Financial Records, 1980. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Financial Records, 1981-1982. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records - National Bank Checking Account, 1972-1974. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records - Tax Exempt Status and Forms, 1978. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Financial Records - Treasurer's Correspondence, 1981. (Box 39, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Place Name Survey of Virginia Files, 1958-1981., Extent: 19 boxes. (Box 39-57)
  The Place Name Survey of Virginia files include records relating to the National Survey, as well as the Virginia Survey. National survey files contain correspondence, newsletters, an organizational history, and essays. Virginia survey files include bibliographies, correspondence, researchers' contact information, financial records, maps and map indexes, publicity information, interoffice memoranda, printing and publishing materials, and reference sources. There are records relating to the field operations of the Virginia Survey, including correspondence, clippings, maps, notes, publications, and pamphlets concerning the tracing of Virginia place names, arranged alphabetically by county, independent city, or larger area where work was focused. The Virginia Survey files als contain publications and forms, including annual reports, minutes, research guidebooks, handbooks, and newsletters of the Place Name Survey of Virginia and other organizations. Finally, there are also card index files on Virginia place names.
  - Administrative Operations - National Survey - Commission, 1978. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Operations - National Survey - Correspondence, 1974. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Operations - National Survey - Correspondence, 1975-1978. (Box 39, Folder 7-8)
  - Administrative Operations - National Survey - Newsletters, 1972-1979. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Operations - National Survey - Organization. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Operations - National Survey - "Place Names, U.S.A.". (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Administration. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Atlas of Virginia, 1975-1978. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Automatic Data Processing, 1976-1978. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Book: Map Bibliography. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Book: Outline, Bibliography, Index. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Chorography. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Contacts. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - General Correspondence, 1973-1978. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: American Name Society, 1974-1980. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Edgar Bingham, 1974-1976. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Mary R. Miller, 1971-1980. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: National Archives, 1974-1980. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Potomac Appalachian Trail Club, 1974-1978. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Pending, 1976. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: U.S. Board on Geographic Names, 1972-1980. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Virginia Department of Highways and Transportation. (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Virginia Folklore Society, 1976-1981. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Virginia Historic Landmark Commission, 1974-1977. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Virginia History and Museums Federation, 1976-1980. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Correspondence: Virginia Independence Bicentennial Commission, 1973-1974. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Funding, 1973-1976. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Funding, 1977-1981. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - General Plans, 1974-1977. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Eastern Historical Geographical Association, 1979. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Map Indexes, 1973-1974. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Map Indexes, 1975-1978. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Map Indexes, Maps, Grids 1975-1978. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Office Notes 1974-1978. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Post Offices, 1971-1978. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Printing. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Publicity, 1974-1979. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Publishers. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Sources, 1968-1977. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Sources. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Terms, 1973-1978. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Operations - Virginia Survey - Workshop, 1976. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Administrative Operations - County and City Surveys - Abbreviations. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Operations - County and City Surveys - Handbook, 1976. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Administrative Operations - County and City Surveys - Handbook (Early Drafts), 1976. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Operations - County and City Surveys - Reasearch Procedures, 1975. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Administrative Operations - Other Records - Correspondence of Douglas Tanner, 1976-1979. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Operations - Other Records - Correspondence of Douglas Tanner, 1980-1981. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Operations - Other Records - Other States Publications, 1975-1979. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Field Operations - Accomack, 1974-1977. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Field Operations - Albemarle, 1963-1981. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Field Operations - Alleghany - Amelia, 1978-1979. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Field Operations - Amherst, 1967-1975. (Box 43, Folder 7)